Senior Search Engine Optimization

Vijay Pandu Gaikwad

Email: - vijaygaikwadseo@gmail.com

viraajg@gmail.com

Mobile: +91-9923605851

Address: Kambre Kamshet Maval Pune Kamshet-410405.

Professional Summary

A dedicated and self driven SEO specialist with extensive experience gained working on a large number of web optimization projects for key clients. Proficient in Local Search Marketing using Review Portals, Social Media Platforms and other Viral Marketing techniques.

A learned SEO Professional focused upon maximizing the visibility of client sites in the digital space, through the management of SEO, Web Analytics, Market Research and Social Media campaigns. Consistently demonstrates the ability to ascertain the exact requirements of the client through extensive research and analysis.

Specialties:

Developing Advance SEO Strategies to increase the visibility of Client Sites.

Executing Link Building Program to crack the Search Engine Algorithms and increase the popularity of the websites.

- About **3+ Years** of **IT** experience in **SEO Expert**.
- Well versed with **Search Engine Optimisation** process which includes Onpage Optimisation as well as Offpage Optimisation.
- In **OnPage Optimisation** I have done keyword analysis & research, competition analysis, keyword segregation, Creating title & metas, Creating ALT tags, Website Analysis.
- In **OffPage Optimisation** I have done Directory submission, Forum Signature linking, Social Bookmarking, Article submission, Profile submission, Web 2.0 submission, Linkwheel submission, Reciprocal Link Building, Press Release Submission, Blog commenting, Micro blogging, RSS feeds, Forum Posting, Create Squidoo lenses & Squidoo Commenting, Solving queries arising from the client side, Prepare Monthly ranking report for Client.
- Email Marketing, PPC & Facebook, Twitter, Linkedin & YouTube Marketing
- I used tools in SEO Process these are Rank Tracker tool for ranking report, Scrape box, Market Samurai, Senuke X.

Senior Search Engine Optimization

Work Experience

• Current Employer: Weboptims

• **Post**: SEO Manager

• **Duration**: Feb 2013 to Till date

• **Current Employer** : Ceylon Infotech (<u>www.ceyloninfotech.com</u>)

• Post : SEO Team Lead

• **Duration** : 18 Apr 2012 To 25 Feb 2013

• Previous Employer : Kruti Technology (<u>www.krutitech.com</u>)

• Post : SEO Expert

• **Duration** : Apr 2010 To Apr 2012

Education

- M.C.A. in Computer from B.R. Gholap College, Sangvi, Pune University with 57% in 2009
- BSc in Chemistry from Modern College, Pune with 69% in 2006
- H.S.C. Examination with 57 % Pune Board from Lonavla, Pune in 2003
- S.S.C Examination with 69.46% under Pune Board from Talegaon, Pune in 2001

Technical Skills

Programming Languages: PHP, C, Basic knowledge of Java.

Web Technologies : HTML, CSS

CMS : Wordpress

Databases : MySQL
Web Server : Xampp
Operating Systems : Windows

Senior Search Engine Optimization

Personal Details

Name: - Vijay Pandu Gaikwad

Nationality: - Indian

Languages: - English, Hindi, and Marathi.

Pan No: - ALTPG2632E